She's having my baby, and she's not here yet.
她將生下我的小孩,她卻還沒來
-Has her water broken yet? -I don't know.
-她的羊水破了嗎? -我不知道
When we talked,she said she'd already passed the mucous plug.
她和我通話時說她已分泌粘液
Do we have to know about that?
我們需要知道這一些嗎?
What'll you do when you have a baby?
喬伊,你有小孩時你會怎麼做?
I'll be in the waiting room, handing out cigars.
我會在等待室中送雪茄
Joey's made arrangements to have his baby in a movie from the '50s.
喬伊準備讓他孩子出生在50年代的電影中
She could be giving birth in the cab.
我不敢相信她可能會在計程車中生產
Relax. It's only $2 for the first contraction...
羅斯,冷靜點第一次收縮收費二塊錢
...and then 50 cents for each additional contraction.
之後每收縮一次收五毛錢
What,it's okay when Chandler does it?
什麼?錢德這樣說時就沒事
You have to pick your moments.
你得選對時間
Did I miss it?
我錯過了嗎?
-She's not here yet. -What's with the guitar?
-沒有,她根本還沒出現 -幹嘛帶吉他來?
We might be here for a while. Things might get musical.
我想我們會在這兒待一陣子,來點音樂
-Where have you been? -We stopped at the gift shop.
-你到底上哪兒去了? -我們中途在禮品店待了一會兒
I got this, and Susan wanted a Chunky.
我想買這個,蘇珊想買「矮胖」
You're having a baby. You don't stop for Chunkies.
你就快生小寶寶了. 是小寶寶不能中途下車買矮胖
I used to have that bumper sticker.
我過去也用那個汽車貼紙
You see what I mean?
懂我意思嗎?
The One With the Birth
六人行 第1季 第23集 本出世
-=BT之家DRM小組 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 榮譽出品 河馬根據網絡字幕微調製作
-"Stopped for a Chunky." -Let it go,Ross.
-下車買矮胖 -別介意了,羅斯
I got an extra one. You want this?
我多了一個,想要嗎?不想
-How's my favorite parenting team? -Dr. Franzblau.
-我最喜愛的父母團隊好 -法大夫
I understand you're thinking of having a baby.
我瞭解你們在考慮生寶寶的事
I see you're nine months pregnant. That's a good start.
我知道你已懷胎九月 這是好的開始
-How are your contractions? -I love them.
-收縮的情況如何? -我喜歡
Each one's like a little party in my uterus.
每一陣都像是子宮中的小舞會
-Every 4 minutes,lasting 55 seconds. -59 seconds. Quartz.
-每4分鐘,持續55秒 -59秒,石英表
Swiss quartz.
瑞士石英表
-Am I allowed to drink anything? -lce chips.
-我能喝飲料嗎? -碎冰
-At the nurse's station. -I'll get it!
-護士站有 -我去拿
-No,I'll get it. -No,I'm getting it.
-不,我去,馬上回來 -不,我去…
Hi. Thought you might like some ice chips.
我想你或許想喝碎冰謝謝
-Thanks. -And if you need anything else l...
-謝謝. -如果還需要別的…
...do not believe we've met.
我沒見過吧?
I'm Rachel Greene.
我叫瑞秋格林
I'm Carol's ex-husband's sister's roommate.
卡蘿前任丈夫妹抹的室友
Nice to meet you. I'm Dr. Franzblau.
幸會,我是法大夫
I'm your roommate's brother's ex-wife's obstetrician.
你室友哥哥前妻的醫生
Oh,that's funny.
真有趣
I want a baby.
我要個寶寶
Not tonight,honey. I got an early day tomorrow.
今晚不行,親愛的我明天得早起
-Get up. Let's get some coffee. -Okay,because we never do that.
-起來,我們去買咖啡 -好吧,因為我們沒做過
Shoot,shoot,shoot. Or just fall down. That's good too.
投.投.投.或是不進也行
Knick fan?
尼克斯迷?
-Oh,boy,do they suck. -Listen,lady
-他們爛透了 -聽著,女士
Look. Look at your man,Ewing.
看,你的尤恩
He couldn't hit water if he was standing on a boat.
他連坐在船上都投不進水裡
-And who do you like? -Celtics.
-是嗎?你支持誰? -凱爾特人
Celtics? They couldn't hit a boat if
凱爾特人?他們不可能擊中船隊的如果
Wait....
等等
They suck,all right?
反正他們很爛
Shut up. It's a rebuilding year
閉嘴,今年是重建年
Let me get the father. We need a father over here.
我幫你叫孩子的爹,我們這兒需要爸爸…
There's no father.
這裡沒有爸爸
-Oh,sorry. -That's okay. I'm fine.
-抱歉 -沒關係,我沒事
Okay. Right this way.
這邊來
All the other pregnant women seem to be going in here.
所有的孕婦似乎都往這兒走
They're tiny and chubby And so sweet to touch
他們又小又肉摸起來感覺很好
But soon they'll grow up And resent you so much
不久他們長大後就會開始恨你
Now they're yelling at you And you don 't know why
現在他們對你大吼大叫,你不知原因為何
And you cry and you cry And you cry
你只能哭啊,哭啊,你哭啊
-Thanks,Ross. -I'm paying you to stop.
-謝謝,羅斯 -用來叫你停止的好吧
Oh,look,twins. Hi,guys. Oh,cute.
看,是雙胞胎,好可愛
No fair.
不公平
I don't even have one. How come they get two?
我一個都沒有,他們怎會有兩個?
-You'll get one. -When?
-你也會有的 -什麼時候?
Tell you what. When we're 40, if neither of us are married...
好吧,告訴你.我們40歲時如果都還單身
...what do you say we have one?
我們就一起生一個,如何?
Why won't I be married when I'm 40?
為何我40歲時還單身?
I just meant hypothetically.
不,這只是假設
Hypothetically,why won't I be married when I'm 40?
假設為何我到40歲時還單身?
What is it? Is there something unmarriable about me?
為什麼?我有不適婚姻的毛病嗎?
Well?
好吧?
Dear God! This parachute is a knapsack.
親愛的上帝!這降落傘是個背包
Look at you,dressy-dress.
看你,盛裝登場
Did you go home and change?
你回家換衣服?
It's an important day. I want to look nice.
今天是個重要的日子,我想漂亮一點
Has Dr. Franzblau been by?
法大夫來了嗎?
I haven't seen him.
不,我們還沒見到他
Where is he? He is supposed to be here.
他在哪兒?他應該在這兒的
What if the baby needs him?
萬一小孩需要他怎麼辦?
What's the deal with you and doctors? Is your father a doctor?
瑞秋,你和醫生到底是怎麼了 難道你爸也是個醫生?
Yeah. Why?
對,幹嘛問?
No reason.
沒理由
Mom,we've been through this.
媽媽,我們能過這個
No,I am not calling him.
不,我不找他
I don't care if it is his kid, the guy's a jerk.
我不管這是不是他的孩子,他是個大渾蛋
No,I am not alone. Joey's here.
不,我不是一個人,喬伊在這兒
What do you mean "Joey who"?
什麼意思?喬伊什麼?
Joey who?
喬伊什麼?
-Tribbiani. -Joey Tribbiani.
-崔比歐尼 -喬伊崔比歐尼
Yes. Okay. Hold on.
對,等等
She wants to talk to you.
她要跟你談
Take the phone.
拿著電話
Yeah,it's me.
對,是我
No,we're just friends.
不,我們只是朋友
Yeah,I'm single.
對,我單身
Twenty-five.
25歲
An actor. Hello?
演員
She's not much of a phone person.
她不善於講電話
So,what's the deal with this father guy?
孩子的爸怎麼了?
If someone was having my baby, I'd wanna know about it.
如果有人即將生下我的孩子,我會想知道的
Hey,Knick fan,am I interested in your views on fatherhood? No.
尼克斯迷,你對爸爸的觀點我不在乎
-Maybe I should just go. -Maybe you should.
-或許吧我應該走了. -也許應該
Good luck...
祝你好運
...and take care.
保重了
The Celtics problem is that the players run the team.
你知道凱爾特人有什麼問題? 他們讓球員經營球隊這不是真的
-That is so not true. -Oh,it is.
-這不是真的 -這當然是真的
-Breathe. -Breathe.
-深呼吸 -深呼吸
You're gonna kill me.
你們會害死我的
-Fifteen more seconds. 1 4,1 3,1 2 -Count faster.
-剩15秒 -14,13,12數快點
It'll be okay. IKeep focusing on Jordy. He'll be here soon.
你會沒事,記得這樣做全是為了裘帝,他馬上就到了
-Three. Two. Who the hell is Jordy? -Your son.
-3,2,1.裘帝到底是誰? -你兒子
I don't have a son named Jordy. We all agreed on Jamie.
不,我不要我兒子叫裘帝, 我們協議過,我兒子叫潔米
Jamie was the name of Susan's first girlfriend...
潔米是蘇珊第一任女友的名字
...so we went back to Jordy.
所以我們決定還是用裘帝
What do you mean,back to Jordy? We never landed on Jordy.
這是什麼意思?還是用裘帝, 我們根本沒討論過裘帝
We just passed by it during the whole Jesse-Cody-Dillon fiasco.
我們討論過傑西科德迪倫時提到一下
Ow! Leg cramp!
我腳抽筋
-I got it. -I got it. I'm doing it.
-我明白了 -明白,我來處理
You get to sleep with her. I get the cramps.
你和她睡覺,我來處理抽筋
No,you don't.
你不行
That is it. I want both of you out.
夠了,你們都給我出去
-She started it. -He did.
-什麼?是她引起的… -他…
I'm trying to get a person out of my body here...
我不管,我想生下小孩
...and you're not making it any easier! Now go!
你們在這兒根本是愈幫愈忙
-Thanks. -See what you did?
-謝謝 -看你幹了什麼?
-Listen -Out!
-聽著 -出去!
Breathe. Breathe.
深呼吸.深呼吸
What is that? Something exploded.
怎麼了?有東西爆炸了
-That's not the baby,is it? -Her water broke. Calm down.
-不是嬰兒 -她的羊水破了,冷靜點
Water breaking? What do you mean? What's that?
羊水破了?你什麼意思?
Breathe. Breathe.
深呼吸.深呼吸
I'm okay. I'm okay. That's disgusting. I'm okay.
我很好,我很好,這樣真討厭,我很好
-This is so your fault. -How is this my fault?
-這都是你的錯 -為什麼都是我的錯?
Carol never threw me out of a room before you.
你們在一起之前卡蘿從未把我趕出房間
There's a lot of things Carol never did before me.
我出現之前有許多事卡蘿沒做過
-Are you trying to be clever? -You're so threatened by me.
-知道你的問題出在哪兒嗎? -你因我而感到岌岌可危
Hey. Okay,all right. That's it. Get in here.
嘿,ok,好吧,就這樣,進去
My God,you guys. I don't believe you.
天哪,夥計們,我簡直不敢相信你們兩個
There are children coming into the world here...
小寶寶即將誕生在這棟建築
...and your fighting isn't the first thing they should hear.
他聽見的第一個聲音不該是你們的吵鬧聲
So stop all the yelling! Just stop it!
所以你們別再吵了
Don't make me do this again! I don't like my voice like this!
對,蘇珊,別讓我再發一次脾氣 我不喜歡我自己這樣
Who wants to hear something ironic?
誰想聽反諷的事?
Are they here yet?
他們到了嗎?
Don't worry, we're gonna find them.
不要擔心,我們會找到他們那的
And until we do, we are all here for you. Okay?
找到人之前,我們都會在這兒陪你的
You were telling me about Paris. It sounds wonderful.
你告訴我巴黎的事真棒
There was this great little pastry shop right by my hotel
那家糕餅店就在我住的飯店隔壁
There you go,dear.
加油,加油,親愛的
-You find them? -Not in the gift shop or cafeteria....
-你找到他們啦? -不是在禮品店或者咖啡廳
Where are Phoebe and Joey?
菲比和喬伊在哪裡?
There's something sinister going on here.
我想這裡有點險惡
If you find anyone, or parts of anyone...
如果你找到任何人,或者任何人的一部分
...scream. And scream again.
就大叫,不停的大叫
-Help! -Come on!
-救命! -拜託
-I'm having a baby in there! -Hello!
-我在這裡生孩子! -hello
Okay,everyone stand back.
大家退後
Ow.
噢
All right,good thing we're in a hospital.
好吧,好的是我們在醫院裡
Come on,Lydia,you can do it.
加油,莉迪亞,你辦得到
Push him out,push him out. Harder,harder.
用力,用力,使勁,使勁
Push him out,push him out. Way out.
用力,用力,推他出來
Let's get that ball and really move.
我們搶球而且真的動了
Let's get
我們…
I was just Yeah,okay. Push,push,push.
我只是,ok,用力,用力,用力
What are you gonna do, suck the door open?
你想幹嘛?將門吸開?
Help! Help!
救命!救命!
And they found their bodies The very next day
第二天,他們終於發現他們的屍體
And they found their bodies The very next
他們終於發現他們的屍體
Mom,everything's going fine.
媽媽,一切順利
Ross is great.
對,羅斯很好
He's in a whole other place.
他在其他地方
No,he's gone.
不,他不見了
No,you don't have to fly back. Really.
不,你們不用飛回來.真的
What do you mean "This might be your only chance"? I'm only 26.
我唯一的機會?什麼意思?我才26歲
I'm not even thinking about babies yet.
我連小孩的事都沒想過
-Where have you been? -I just had a baby.
-你上哪兒去了? -我剛生了個小孩
Mazel tov.
了不起
It could be one hour or three.
說不定,或許是一小時也可能是三小時
But relax. She's doing great.
別請放心,她的狀況良好
So tell me,are you currently involved with anyone?
告訴我,目前有對象嗎?
Not at the moment,I'm not. Are you?
沒有,現在沒有,你呢?
No,it's hard enough to get women to go out with me.
沒有,我不容易找到對像
Right. Yeah,I've heard that about cute doctors.
對,我聽過有關帥哥大夫的傳間
No,really. I suppose it's because I spend so much time,you know...
沒有,真的.我想這是因為我花了太多的時間
...where I do.
在工作上
I try not to let work affect my personal life.
我試著不讓工作影響我的生活
But it's hard when,when you do what I do. It's,like....
當你做的時候很難,當我做,像…
Well,for instance, what do you do?
等等,你從事什麼工作?
I'm a waitress.
我是服務生
Aren't there times when you come home at night and you're,like:
難道你下班回家後不會覺得…
"If I see one more cup of coffee...."
如果我再看見咖啡杯…
Gotcha.
我懂
-I'm gonna check up on your friend. -That's fine.
-我去看看你朋友. -很好
-How'd you know I was here? -Your mom called me.
-你怎麼會知道我在這兒? -你媽打電話告訴我的
So is this her?
這就是她?
No,this is a loaner.
不,這是替代品
Ours is at the shop.
我們的還在商店裡
God,I hope she has my brains.
天哪,我希望她有我的頭腦
I'm sorry you had to do this by yourself.
抱歉,讓你自己承擔這一切
I wasn't by myself. I had a doctor, a nurse and a helper guy.
我不是自己一個,我有大夫,護士和善心人士
-So did you see who won the game? -The Knicks by 10. They suck.
-知道誰贏嗎? -尼克斯勝十分,他們真爛
They're not so bad.
他們還不算是太爛
Come on. Come on.
拜託,拜託
-You're doing it too hard. -You have to do it hard or else
-你做的太辛苦了. -你應該更努力或者其他什麼
Damn it. Damn it.
可惡,可惡
Damn it,damn it. This is all your fault.
可惡…都是你的錯
This should be the greatest day of my life.
這本來是我今生最快樂的日子
My son is being born, and I should be in there.
我兒子即將出世,我應該在那兒的
Instead,I'm stuck in a closet with you.
而不是被困在這兒
I have been waiting for this as much as you.
我和你一樣期待已久
No one's been waiting for this as much as I have.
不,相信我沒人像我如此期待
You know what's funny?
你知道什麼最搞笑嗎?
You go home with the baby. Where does that leave me?
諷刺的是你們將帶著寶寶回家 我剩下什麼?
You're his father.
你是他父親
Who am l? There's Father's Day. There's Mother's Day.
我是誰?這世上有父親節,母親節
There's no Lesbian Lover Day.
卻沒有女同志節
Every day is Lesbian Lover Day.
每天都是女同志節
This is so great.
這真精彩
Do you wanna explain that?
願意解釋嗎?
I mean,when I was growing up, my dad left...
因為我小時候我爸離開
...and my mother died and my stepfather went to jail.
我媽過世,我繼父入獄
I barely had enough pieces to make one whole parent.
我根本得不到父母的愛
And here's this baby who has three whole parents...
如今他有如此愛他的三個父母
...who fight over who gets to love it the most...
甚至為誰給他的愛最多而吵架
...and it's not even born yet.
而且他根本還未出世
It's just the luckiest baby in the whole world.
他真是全天下最幸福的寶寶
I'm sorry. You were fighting.
抱歉,你們正在吵架
Where are they?
他們在哪兒?
-They'll be here. -They wouldn't miss this.
-他們在哪兒? -他們不會錯過的
Relax. You're only at 9 centimeters, and the baby's at zero station.
放輕鬆.才開九公分,寶寶沒那麼快出來
You are really frightening me.
你嚇到我了
Somebody wanna help me? Trying to rip out my heart.
誰願意幫我嗎?她想掏出我的心臟
That's great. Anybody seen a nipple?
這下可好,有人看見乳頭嗎?
Ten centimeters. Here we go.
十公分,開始用力
-Time to start pushing. -But they're not here yet.
-開始用力 -他們還沒好
-I can't tell the baby to wait. -Oh,God.
-我無法叫寶寶等他們來 -哦,上帝
-Okay,got the vent open. -Hi,I'm Ben.
-通氣口開了 -我是本
I'm hospital worker Ben.
我是醫院工人本
It's Ben to the rescue.
本前來搶救了
Ben,you ready? Give me your foot.
本,準備好沒?腳給我
On three,Ben. One,two,three.
數到三,本.1,2,3
Come on,Ben. That's it,Ben.
來吧,本.就是這樣,本
What do you see?
你看見什麼?
I see what appears to be a dark vent.
我看見黑暗的通氣孔
Wait.
等等
Yes,it is,in fact,a dark vent.
真的是黑暗的通氣孔
Pheebs,it's open. It's open.
菲比,門開了
Wait. You forgot your legs.
等等,你們忘了腳
-Push. Push. -We're here. We're here.
-用力,用力 -我們來了,我們來了
Where have you been?
你們上哪兒去了
Long story.
說來話長
I need you to keep pushing. I need Excuse me,can I have this?
卡蘿,我要你不斷用力 抱歉,我能用這個…
There's too many people here. There's about to be one more.
這裡人太多了,而且待會兒又會多一個
So if you're not an ex-husband or lesbian life partner,out you go.
所以不是前任丈夫和女同志終身伴侶者請出去
-Bye-bye. -Good luck,you guys.
-再見了…? -祝你好運.夥計
Do you have to be Carol's lesbian life partner?
我問你,要卡蘿的女同志終身伴侶才行嗎?
Out.
出去
Here he comes.
他的頭露出來了
Let me see. I've gotta see.
讓我看看…我看到了
A head.
是頭…
It's huge. How are you doing this?
好大,卡蘿,你是怎麼辦到的?
You're not helping.
你真是一點忙都幫不上
You're doing great.
你做得很好…
-Hello? -Oh,sorry.
-你好? -哦,對不起
What do you see? What do you see?
你看見什麼?你看見什麼?
We got a head. We got arms. Oh,look at the little fingers.
我看到到頭,手臂出來了,看看這些小手指
A chest and a stomach...
看,是手指,肚子
...and it's a boy,definitely a boy.
是男的,百分百男孩
Legs,knees and feet.
腿,膝蓋和腳
He's here.
他出來了
He's a person.
他是個人
-Look. -What does he look like?
-看. -他看起來像誰?
IKind of like my Uncle Ed, covered in Jell-O.
像我叔叔艾德,被果凍包著
Really?
真的?
You guys,he's beautiful.
各位,他好漂亮
Thanks,Pheebs.
謝了,菲比
No shouting,but we still need a name for this little guy.
不准大吼,我們仍需要為他取個名字
-How about Ben? -I like Ben.
-本如何? -我喜歡本
Ben.
本
Ben's good. How come you never mentioned Ben before?
這名字不錯,你們之前怎沒提過這名字?
We just cooked it up.
剛想出來的
That's what we were off doing.
這就是我們不在時做的事
-Can we come in? -Yeah,come on.
-我們能進來嗎? -當然,請進
I know. I know.
我知道,我知道
Everybody,there's someone I'd like you to meet.
各位,向你們介紹一個人
-This is Ben. -Hi,Ben.
-他叫本. -嗨,本
Ben,this is everybody.
本,這是大家
Susan,he looks just like you.
蘇珊,他看起來像你
Thanks.
謝謝
I can't believe one of us actually has one of these.
天啊,沒想到我們之中有人生寶寶了
I know. I still am one of these.
我知道,我也是其中之一
Can l?
我能嗎?
Okay,the head. You gotta....
好,頭,你必須…
I'm your Aunt Monica. Yes,I am.
本,我是你姑姑摩妮卡,沒錯
I'm your Aunt Monica.
我就是你姑姑摩妮卡
I will always have gum.
我將永遠有…牙齒
Ben...
本…
... I want you to know that there may be some times when...
我要你知道有時我會不在
... I may not be around like this.
像這樣
But I'll still always come back...
我會回來
...Iike this.
像這樣
And sometimes, I may be away longer...
有時我會離開更久
...Iike this.
像這樣
But I'll still always come back...
我仍會回來
...Iike this.
像這樣
And sometimes,I'll want you to steal third and I'll go like this:
有時我要你到三壘,我會這樣
He is so amazing.
他太神奇了
Yeah,I know. Look at him.
對,我知道,你看他
Nothing. I don't think that's his name.
沒反應,我想他不喜歡這名字
Look,he's closing his eyes.
看,他閉上眼睛了
Look,he's opening his eyes.
看,他張開眼睛了
He doesn't do much,does he?
他不常動吧?
Nope,this is pretty much it.
這樣已算動了
You guys wanna get some coffee?
你們想喝咖啡嗎?
I'll see you guys later.
待會兒見
He's closing his eyes again.
看,他又閉上眼睛了